Joshua (En Young) Lai

Alhambra, CA. 91801

Cell: (626) 617 – 2106 • Email: Joshua.Lai.621@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Release Engineer/Manager, Information Security Analyst and PCI Compliance Lead skilled to tackle complicated problems with positive attitudes and no bias when working with team members. Utilized and enhanced the skills and techniques developed over the course of a career in performing various projects. The expertise, abilities, dependability and accomplishments were valued throughout the completed tasks. Obtained skills in the following areas:

ClearQuest	MS Visio	• PL/SQL	Unix/Linux/AIX	• LDAP/ADAM
• SVN/TSVN	 AirWatch 	 Toad/Teradata 	• Perl/C/C++	• LDIFDE/CSVDE
• Trac	 Splunk 	 SmartSheet 	• Java	 Nessus
• Jira	• Git	BitBucket	Shell Scripting	 Business Objects

WORK EXPERIENCE

Smart and Final Stores - Commerce, CA.

2006 - 2017

Software Release Engineer/Configuration Management (2012 – 2017)

Performed software releases independently in liaison with the development team, managing source control for configuration items in test and production environments on various platforms. Managed over forty source controlled repositories. Duties are as followed:

- Released applications to ALL environments in a timely manner to meet company milestones according to the policy, processes and procedures.
- Implemented/integrated ClearQuest and Subversion to optimize the change management process to increase developer's workflow.
- Created Subversion repositories and managed user accesses for all projects.
- Provided install logs to Auditors during Audit season using custom Unix/Linux scripts and Subversion history logs.
- Written Software Configuration Management Plan (SCMP) and other internal change management/release procedures for various projects.
- Facilitated training for developers of best practices in creating Subversion branches for development releases
- Facilitated training for developers on how to use commands and functions using the TortoiseSVN, SVN and ClearQuest tools.
- Staged and performed releases using the TortoiseSVN and SVN (In Unix/Linux/AIX Environments) tools using methods such as Merging, Branching and Tagging.
- Performed Mobile.ipa releases using the AirWatch tool.
- Performed Database Object releases using custom scripts and the PL/SQL Developer tool.
- Created and modified custom scripts to execute and log the installation processes on the Linux/Unix/AIX environment.
- Implemented branching methods for production releases in order to ensure implementers used the approved software configuration items for production release (e.g. Created SVN Tags for DB Release).
- Co-chaired weekly Software Change Control Board meetings and chaired the meeting on an as needed basis.
- Utilized SmartSheet for Project Management using the Kanban and Gantt methods
- Currently in the process of utilizing Git with BitBucket for versioning and JIRA for Defect Tracking

Cyber Security Analyst (2014 – 2017)

Analyzed and investigated security events to mitigate suspicious activities and vulnerabilities by utilizing the following security tools: Splunk Enterprise Security, Nessus, CounterAct, Lansweeper, Carbon Black, Cylance, SEPM, McAfee, Tripwire, Palo Alto, AirDefense and TippingPoint. Also completed the following:

- Installed and configured Splunk Enterprise, Splunk ES and Splunk TA's to meet Splunk Best Practice recommendations and created Splunk App, Reports and Dashboards for users.
- Added new Splunk indexes, leveraging Splunk trend anomalies and fixed security events for Splunk instances
- Created and maintained Cardholder Data Environment and Splunk Architecture Diagram utilizing MS Visio
- Led and completed TR-39/PCI PIN Security Compliance, 2016 PCI DSS 3.1 & 2017 PCI DSS 3.2 Compliance audit.
- Review Palo Alto, AirDefense and TippingPoint Daily Reports for Suspicious Activities and Vulnerabilities
- Created Nessus Policies to automate Vulnerability & Audit Scans and PEN Tests

QA Analyst – CTFL (2010 – 2013)

Performed tests on various applications built on various platforms including Mobile Devices (iPhone & iPad), .NET, Oracle, UNIX including the Mainframe system. Worked closely with various development teams on major projects and determined which levels of test method to employ in order to meet the company's milestone and collecting required documents. Also completed in the following:

- Analyzed, tested, implemented, and improved software development process by utilizing accurate configuration items data in each of its releases; it reduced release cycle time by half of its original.
- Performed tests with developers and users using Code Reviews and Unit Testing to meet the business needs and requirements.
- Performed independent testing on systems using Test Cases provided by the developer using the Functional Area and Performance Testing methods to validate accuracy of the business sales reports.
- Performed tests on Mobile applications using the iPhone and iPad by ensuring the data displayed are accurate and viewable which provided users with confident when viewing sales reporting.
- Wrote queries to verify and compare data for tests using PL/SQL Developer, TOAD and Teradata tool, as a result, enhanced data integrity.

QS Coordinator (2006 – 2010)

Utilized problem solving skills to the extent in using the ClearQuest tool to manage Software Change Requests. The skills and knowledge achieved from was the development life cycle and the release process with various IT development teams. Also completed in the following:

- Involved in all SQA activities to ensure all documents are provided and requirements meets the SQA Entrance and Exit Criteria.
- Administrated and maintained ClearQuest to accurately generate the current state of a bug fix/feature enhancement and the overall project evaluation for project managers/developers to better assist on their software development.
- Assumed responsibilities for all documentations on all Change Requests submitted to ClearQuest
- Made independent responsible decisions during critical times to meet the business needs and requirements
- Generated and distributed reports for Change Management Control Board Meetings which provided clear descriptions of the latest status and state of projects.

Access Request/LDAP Administrator (2006 – 2010)

Ensured all requested access to applications meets the user's identity and business needs in a timely manner. Exceled in team collaboration and solution brainstorming. Applied and maintained a friendly service mentality is a must in order to satisfy all users' needs. The followings are additional information of responsibilities and involvements:

- Utilized the company's API In House build Application called LDAP.
- Acquired the hands-on experience and knowledge working in a professional environment as a team member that allowed mental maturity and the highest respect for all aspects of the engineering field.
- Interacted with associates in all departments
- Constantly maintained a sturdy communication with Application Business Owners, Customers and Application Administrators
- Enforced all required policies to ensure all procedures meet auditing requirements
- Improved the Access Request Plans and Procedure documentation to clearly identify the Access Request's processes
- Involved in auditing reviews and provided all required documents

Systempro Computer Inc. - City of Industry, CA

2004 - 2006

Computer Technician

Enhanced my skills and knowledge of a simple computer in this prominent diminutive company. Assisted as a salesperson and a technician at most of the computer fairs. This position requires a person with swift problem solving skills and must be versatile. The followings are the knowledge and skills gained from and used for this company:

- Utilized multitasking skills by building multiple computers while installing drivers and software on others
- Enhanced skills and perception to a higher level of quality control
- Assembled a whole new robust computer from scratch
- Gained a better understanding of how does the computer hardware and software collaborated with each other
- Gained further knowledge of various computer part's features and functions
- Ran tests on every new system to assure all drives are robust before releasing the system with a QA perspective
- Assisted on phone and human interaction with Tech Support when required
- Handled most of the Quality Control to ensure a high quality computer system

MODCOMP Inc - Ft. Lauderdale, FL

1999 - 2000

Intern Software Engineer

Exceled in team collaboration and solution brainstorming. Applied rigor and creativity that combined knowledge learned from school research; human-computer interaction, and graphic design to solve diverse GUI design issues.

- Utilized the company's API (Viewmax) to modernize the user interface
- Co-wrote programs and implemented them using HTML and JavaScript also assisted in minor Java Applications
- Implemented new GUI demos for both Pocket PC (using Web Clipping) and cellular phones (using WML and WMLScript) that enhanced salesperson to insure an error free environment when presenting the company's demo to vendors. Managed all phases of GUI for the interactive and transactional e-commerce site for the demo.
- Acquired the hands-on experience and knowledge working in a professional environment as a team member that allowed mental maturity and the highest respect for all aspects of the engineering field.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

- B.S., Computer Engineering, Florida Atlantic University, Bacon Raton, FL
- Certificate for Introduction to Cyber Security 2015
- Certificate for Advanced Excel 2003 2011
- Certificate for Intermediate Excel 2003 2011
- Certified Tester, Foundation Level 2010